你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
欢迎回来。
And welcome back.
现在，在这段视频中，我们将讨论如何将您的运动能力带到下一个
Now in this video we're going to be discussing how you can take your sporting abilities to the next
级别，了解如何对表格格式的数据进行排序，以便表中的数据按
level by looking at how you can sort data that is in tabular format so data that comes in tables by
向你展示如何打开不同的栏目。
showing you how you can sort of open down various columns.
这非常酷，因为这意味着您可以直接从
Now this is super cool because it means that you can do all this kind of data sorting right from the
命令行您不需要打开电子表格软件。
command line you don't need to open up a spreadsheet software.
你可以直接在航站楼里做，省去所有多汁多汁的处理能力。
You can do it right there in the terminal and save all that juicy juicy processing power.
因此，让我们继续直接开始，看看它是如何工作的。
So let's go ahead and jump right into it and see how this works.
好的，有时候你会从你的命令中得到很多数据。
All right so sometimes you get a lot of data out of your commands.
其中一个例子是带有l选项的ls命令，因此LS破折号L命令。
And one example of this is the ls command with the l option so the LS dash L command.
例如，如果我们在ETSI文件夹上执行。
So for example if we did the on the ETSI folder.
这是包含所有系统配置文件的秋季，您可以看到我们刚刚
So this is the fall that contains all of the system configuration files and you can see that we just
得到一大堆结果。
get a whole bunch of results.
这就像是你从那里得到了很多很多的东西。
It's like you just get loads and loads and loads of stuff coming out of that.
好的。
OK.
但是您知道，为了更容易理解，让我们把它传递给head命令，然后获取
But you know just to make this a bit easier to see let's just pass that into the head command and get
前20行。
the first 20 lines.
我们已经有了输出的前20行。
And that we are there the first 20 lines of output.
好的，那么如果我们想要按列对此数据进行排序，那该怎么办呢？
OK so what if we wanted to sort this data by the column.
那么，如果我们想要按某些列进行排序，实际上可以在SORT命令中使用
So what if we wanted to sort by certain columns you can actually do that in the sort command using the
k选项。
K option.
举个例子，如果我们现在想要排序，我猜这个关于文件大小的列是这样的
So for example if we wanted to sort by now I guess this column which is about the file size is so you
请看这里的这一列，该列都是关于文件大小的，因此可能需要按日期排序，例如
see this one here that this column is all about file sizes so maybe want to sort by date for example
我们想要按日期排序，可能是这几列或其他什么。
and we wanted to sort by date which would be these few columns or whatever.
您可以在SORT命令中完成所有这些操作。
You can do all that in the sort command.
所以，让我们看看我们将如何着手做这件事。
So let's just see how we might go about doing this.
那么，如果我只清除屏幕，那么我们是如何做到的呢？您可以将它输入到SORT命令中，然后将所有数据输入到
So how we do it if I just clear the screen is you'd pipe it into the sort command all the data into
排序命令，并为其提供k选项。
the sort command and you give it the k option.
现在，在K选项之后，您需要告诉排序命令如何使用什么排序对此输入进行排序
Now after the K option you need to tell the sort command how to sort this input using what the sort
命令调用键定义或键定义。
command calls a key definition or a key def.
好的，顺便说一下，这些都在手册页上了。
OK this is all in the man page by the way.
不过，让我向你展示一下它是如何工作的。
But let me show you how it works.
首先告诉它应该按哪一列排序。
First you tell it what column it should sort by.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我稍微往上滚动一点，你就可以看到我们之前得到的结果。
So if I just scroll up a little bit you can see our results that we got before.
我们想用这些大数字按列排序。
We want to sort by the column with these big numbers here.
好的。
OK.
现在，正如我所说的，这些数字实际上是以字节为单位的文件大小。
Now those numbers as I said are actually file sizes in bytes.
假设我们想要从大到小对文件进行排序。
So let's say we want to sort of files from largest to smallest.
好的，那么首先我们需要给出键def，我们想要按其排序的列号，比如说，如果我们计算这里的
OK so first we need to give the key def the column number we want to sort by say if we count here's
第1栏。
column 1.
这也是一列，这是第三列。
So that's one column too that's column 3.
那是第4列，那是第5列。
That's column 4 and that's column 5.
好的，列号是5。
OK so the column number is five.
所以如果我们回到我知道的。
So if we come back to I know.
快点，我要打5字了。
Come on I'm going to type 5.
好的。
OK.
然后你需要说出来，然后你基本上就可以通过了。
Then you need to tell it and then you basically can pass it.
我们喜欢的任何其他选项。
Any other options that we like.
例如，如果我们想要按数字排序，我们可以键入AK，您可以传递任何您喜欢的选项
For example if we want to sort numerically we would type an AK and you can pass any options you like
因此，如果您想要反向排序，您也可以像在上一个视频中看到的那样，在那里键入AWE
so if you wanted to sort reverse you type in awe there as well just like you've seen in the last video
你想要独一无二的你，仅此而已。
you wanted unique type of you and that's it.
这就是你对“让我们现在就到此为止”的关键定义。
That's how you make your key definition of let's just have the end for now.
我们在这里要说的是，好的，列出anssi文件夹中的所有内容，取前20行
So what we're saying here is a ok listo everything that's in the Anssi folder take the first 20 lines
然后按第五列排序。
and then sort it by the fifth column.
好的。
OK.
当我们按Enter键时，我们将看到是的，实际上数据已经按第五列进行了排序
And when we press Enter we'll see that yes actually the data has been sorted by the fifth column you
可以看到，我们首先从最小的文件开始。
can see that we're starting with the smallest files first.
我一直工作到最大的。
I'm working all the way up until the biggest.
但实际上我们想要的是另一种方式，不是吗，我们首先要的是最大的文件。
But actually we wanted it the other way round didn't we we wanted the biggest files first.
因此，如果我们想要实现这一点，我们只需键入Are There。
So if we wanted to make that happen we'll just type in are there.
所以我们说的是按数字排序，但顺序相反。
So we're saying sort numerically but in reverse order.
所以从最大到最小而不是从最小到最大。
So largest to smallest instead of smallest to largest.
记住，默认情况下，排序可以从小到大。
Remembering that the sort can by default go small to big.
现在我们要从大到小。
Now we're going big to small.
所以当我们这样做的时候，我们会看到这一点。
So when we do that we see that yep.
现在我们从大4,096开始，越往下越小。
Now we're starting at big four thousand ninety six and getting smaller as we go down.
这太棒了，就像我们刚刚获取了一大组数据，并按列进行了排序，这就是
So that's supercool right like we've just taken a big set of data and sorted it by columns which is
一种令人惊叹的能力，从我们不需要打开任何像微软这样的东西的那一刻起，我们就可以做到这一点
an amazing ability to be able to just do from the minute we didn't have to open anything like Microsoft
Excel。
Excel.
我们只是直接从命令行对数据进行了排序。
We just sorted the data straight from the command line.
但是您可能会注意到一件事，特别是在LS输出中，这些文件看到了这些文件
But one thing that you might notice especially with the LS output is that these file saw these file
尺码是很难正确解释的。
sizes are kind of hard to interpret right.
这些都是以字节为单位的，我不知道您的情况，但我倾向于以千字节或兆字节来读取内容
These are all in bytes and I don't know about you but I tend to read things in kilobytes or megabytes
或者其中一些，我不倾向于直接以字节为单位读取。
or some of them either I don't tend to read it directly in bytes.
因此，正如您所知道的那样，ls命令有一个选项，允许您读取您知道要提供数据的内容
So as you know the ls command has an option that allows you to read that you know to give the data in
人类可读的格式。
human readable format.
所以如果我们用人类可读的格式这样做，你可以看到现在发生的事情是我们正在得到
So if we do that with a human readable format you can see now that what's happening is we're getting
它设置了千字节的大小，也就是说这是千字节聚焦，我们会得到大约3个
it setting up the amount of kilobytes that said this is for kilobytes focalize we'll get about three
千字节，2.2千字节，那么睡觉就是以字节为单位的，它会说兆字节，千兆字节
kilobytes 2.2 kilobytes and then the rest are just in bytes and it would say megabytes gigabytes whatever
是为了我们正在处理的文件。
it was for files that we're dealing with.
因此，ls命令的hate选项为您提供了人类可读的输出，但是您可能已经注意到了
So it's the hate option for the ls command that gives you human readable output but you may have noticed
这简直是一团糟。
this is just completely messed up.
正确搭配。
Assorting right.
这就像以前我们在完美地排序，就像我们在排序最大的，最小的，在
It's just like before we were sorting perfectly like we were sorting biggest are the top smallest at
在底部。
the bottom.
但现在它只是想做什么就做什么。
But now it's just doing whatever it wants.
原因是当您告诉它使用选项进行数字排序时，锯子就会打开。
And the reason is the saw come on when you tell it to sort numerically with the option.
这与人类可读数据的排序完全不同。
That's a completely different thing to sorting with human readable data.
好的。
OK.
因此，要使其真正与人类可读的数据进行排序，您需要给它提供您所说的选项，并且您
So to make it actually sort with human readable data you need to give it the option you said and you
给它一个选择，你不能同时拥有这两个。
give it the option and you can't have both at the same time.
好的，最后是屏幕，我们现在有了page选项，而不是选项，然后按Enter键。
OK so finally the screen and instead of having the option we now have the page option and we press enter.
现在你可以看到它在工作，我们得到的是最大尺码的上衣和最小尺码的上衣
Now you can see that it's working and we're getting the largest sizes of the top and the smallest at
在底部，仍然以人类可读的格式获得数据，所以我们真的两全其美。
the bottom while still getting the data in human readable format so we get the best of both worlds really.
因此，请记住，如果要按人类可读的数据排序，则需要将排序命令设置为HATE选项
So remember if you want to sort by human readable data you need to give the sort command the hate option
如果您只有一列要处理，它的关键字def或一般情况下。
in its key def or just in general if you've only got one column to deal with.
但是在这里我们必须在那里添加一把钥匙。
But here we had to add a key there.
所以我们在那里输入选项。
So we type the option there.
现在您还可以按月排序。
Now you can also sort by month.
那么让我们看看我们是如何按照这个专栏进行排序的，它是关于您知道的日期和
So let's see how we might sort by this column here which is all about you know the date and the the
文件上次编辑时间。
file was last edited.
那么让我们清理一下屏幕。
So let's clear the screen.
我们来看一下。
Let's take a look.
所以我们的意思是，用人类可读的文件大小，以长格式打印出一个列表。
So we're saying print out a list for us in long form format with human readable file sizes.
ETSI文件夹中的所有内容都是前20行，并按第五列人类可读的顺序进行排序
Everything in the ETSI folder was just the top 20 lines and sort for us by the Fifth Column human readable
可逆的。
reversible.
我把它颠倒过来了。
I got it reversed.
实际上，日期是这一列之后的列，所以我们需要用第五列来代替我们
Well actually the date is the column after this one so we need to have instead of the fifth column we
我要第六栏。
want the sixth column.
因此，如果我们要将5改为6，而不是人类可读的，那么我们将在我们的代码中这样做
So we're going to do it in our code if we're going to change the 5 to 6 and instead of human readable
这将是一个大写的M，K，这将允许我们按月排序。
which is going to put a capital M K that this is going to allow us to sort by month.
如果我现在按Enter键，您可以看到，是的，我们确实已经按月份进行了排序，我们在
And if I press Enter now you can see that yes we have indeed sorted by month and we got January at the
顶部，然后是5月，8月，然后是10月，一直到底部，所以这真的是
top and we've got then may August and then October coming all the way down the bottom so that's really
真的很酷，对吧。
really cool right.
你也可以把它和运算符结合起来，你可以把它和可逆性结合起来，只需在里面加一个R。
You can also as well combine this with ops you can combine it with reversible by putting an R in there.
现在我们来看看是否清除屏幕，您会再次看到10月份在顶部，现在是1月份
And now we'll find out if I clear the screen and again you see that October is at the top and now January
在底部。
is at the bottom.
所以。
So.
这就对了。
So there you go.
就像一旦你理解了这几个不同的选项，你就不会觉得更困难了
Like once you understand these several different options it's really not that much more difficult to
按某些列排序，您所要做的就是排序，它只在基达中，告诉它是哪一列
sort by certain columns all you've got to do is sort it's just in the kida tell it which column that
你想要的。
you want.
现在给你一个挑战。
Now here's a challenge for you.
我想看看你能不能告诉我你会怎么按这个栏目排序。
I want to see whether you can tell me how you might sort by this column.
所以这就是你知道的，最小的数字排在第一位。
So that's the you know the smallest numbers come first.
好的。
OK.
那么你怎么按这个栏目排序呢，吉野在这里有这些数字。
So how would you sort by this column which is Yoshino has these numbers here.
您将如何按列排序，这样最小数字就会先排在前面。
How would you sort by that column so that the smallest number was were first go ahead.
现在暂停视频，然后回来看看您做得如何。
Pause the video videos now and then come back to see how you did.
你过得怎么样。
How did you get on.
你成功了吗。
Did you manage it.
嗯，如果他做得很好，学得真的很快，他的高速公路就会在
Well if he did well done really really quick learning his highway would have gone about doing it at
那一次。
that time.
所以我要做的就是让一切保持不变。
So what I do is we keep everything the same.
LS El-Hage和ATC去掉了前20行，现在唯一的不同是Akki的死亡。
LS El-Hage with the ATC taking out the top 20 lines and now the only difference is Akki death.
好的。
OK.
第一个问题是k选项2，排序命令第一个问题是什么
So the first question would be the k option 2 the sort command What's the first question is what's the
列号所在的代码号。
column number where the code number.
这是第一栏。
This is the first column.
这是右边第二列。
This is the second column right.
所以我们把2放在一起，我们想要用数字来排序。
So let's put two and we want to sort this numerically.
正确的。
Right.
所以我们现在进行数字排序，默认情况下，排序命令是最小的第一个向右。
So we're going sort of numerically now by default the sort command was saut smallest first right.
所以这意味着我们不需要逆转任何事情。
So that means we don't have to reverse anything.
如果我清除屏幕并尝试，默认情况下它将从最小的数字开始。
It will start with the smallest number first by default if I clear the screen and try that.
现在我们可以看到，它已经按此列排序，最小的数字在前面。
Now we see that it has been sorted by this column with the smallest numbers coming first.
如果我们想逆转这一点，我们只需给它一个选择权，它就会逆转这一点。
If we wanted to reverse that we just give it the an option and it would reverse that.
所以现在你得到的是顶部的八个，还有那个。
So now you're getting the eights at the top and the and the.
然后是最小的数字，就是底部的数字。
And then the smallest numbers the ones down the bottom.
所以有很多不同的方法，你可以做到这一点。
So there's loads of different ways that you can you can do this.
但你还是来了。
But there you are.
这就是如何使用SORT命令来对列中的数据和通常的列中的数据进行排序
That's that's how you would use the sort command in order to sort data in columns and in as usual one
我应该注意的是，在这里，我们正在进行一次R。
thing that I should note is here we're having an R.
不管是我写的还是我写的，你写东西的顺序一点也不重要
It doesn't matter if I wrote that or in and it doesn't matter at all like what order you write stuff
在这些关键字定义中。
in these key definitions.
只需将它们视为普通选项，您只需将其放在键定义中即可，这样顺序就不会
Just think of them as normal options that you just put right there in the key definition so order doesn't
物质。
matter.
我们在前两个视频中讲述了大量关于数据排序的内容，在这个视频中，我们
So we've covered a whole lot of stuff in the last two videos about sorting data and in this video we
我们了解了如何使用命令行查看表格式的数据。
took a look at how you would saw data that is in a table format using the command line.
因此，关键是使用带有k选项的排序命令。
And so the key to this was to use the sort command with the k option.
现在，您需要为该选项提供一个称为key def的内容和一个如下所示的密钥
Now you need to give the option something called a key def and a key that follows like this kind of
结构。
structure.
所以首先你要给它一个数字，这个数字就是你要排序的列。
So first you'll give it a number and that number is the column that you'll sort by.
例如，我们这里有数字3，这意味着使用列3进行排序。
So for example we have the number three here and that means sort using column 3.
然后，您可以给它提供您想要的任何其他选项，就像您在上一个视频中看到的那样
Then after that you can give it any other options that you want like you've seen in the last video for
例如，您可以为它提供按数字排序的选项和以相反方式排序的选项。
example you could give it the option to sort numerically and the option to sort in a reverse manner.
所以从最大到最小而不是从最小到最大的人类可读的数据，你会用HAT
So largest to smallest instead of smallest to largest and so human readable data you'd use the hate
选项，而不是AN选项。
option not the an option.
这些是不兼容的，您不能同时使用两者。
And those are incompatible you can't use both at the same time.
因此，如果您有人类可读的数据，那么请使用HATE选项而不是AN选项。
So if you've got human readable data then use the hate option instead of the an option.
就像您在本视频中使用的ls命令一样，您还可以使用以下命令按月进行排序
Like you saw with the ls command that we used in this video and you can also sort using months using
大写M选项，因为SORT命令从小到大排序，所以您会发现
the capital M option and because the Sort commands sort smallest to largest You will find that January
先是十二月，然后是十二月。
comes first and then December comes last.
当然，您也可以使用选项和键定义中的选项顺序来反转
But of course you can reverse that using the option as well and the order of options in the key def
无关紧要。
don't matter.
像往常一样，就像您通常在命令行中输入它们一样，如果您将
As usual just like you were entering them normally on the command line it doesn't matter if you put
然后，或者代替R，然后，顺序并不重要，但要确保您不
in and then or instead of R and then and it doesn't matter the order but just make sure that you don't
具有不兼容的选项，如数字排序和人类可读排序。
have incompatible options such as the numerical sort and the human readable sort.
同时，因为这不会有很好的效果。
At the same time because that won't work very well.
因此，您现在了解了如何使用命令行使用表格排序表格数据对数据进行排序，现在您
So you now know how to sort data using tabular sort tabular data using the command line and now you
应该是使用命令行对数据进行排序的真正大师。
should be really the master of sorting data using the command line.
所以欢迎你。
So Welden you.
所以在下一个视频中，我们要做的是，我们将看到一个令人难以置信的多才多艺的
So in the next video what we're going to do is we're going to take a look at an incredibly versatile
命令称为grep命令。
command called the grep command.
现在，因为在使用命令行时非常有用的一件事是能够搜索
Now because one thing that is super useful when working with the command line is being able to search
通过数据找到我们要找的东西。
through data to find what we are looking for.
好的，只挑出我们感兴趣的部分，grep命令必须是最重要的
OK and pick out just the bits that we're interested in the grep command has got to be one of the most
最常用的命令，它将是您的Linux工具包中一个非常棒的补充。
commonly used commands of all time and it's going to be such an awesome addition to your Linux toolkit.
你可能已经以某种形式或某种形式给人留下了印象，如果你曾经做过一些
You've probably already come across in some form or some form or another if you've ever done some you
我知道在Internet上搜索任何与Linux有关的内容，您可能会遇到grep
know searching around on the internet for anything to do with Linux you probably come across the grep
指挥部。
command.
所以我真的迫不及待地想给你们看这个，并告诉你们如何正确使用它。
So I can't really wait to show you this and show you how to use it properly.
所以如果这些都是好东西，我会在下一个视频中见到你的。
So if all that good stuff I'll see you in the next video.